It's an exciting time to become a visual art teacher
in California.
Single subject art credential program applications
vary at different institutions.
For example, some schools
require a portfolio review
of your own artwork,
while others don't.
So be sure to check
the admissions criteria
for each program to know what you'll need to apply.
At minimum, most programs
will ask you
for subject matter competency in art,
early field experiences,
and an interview.
Subject matter competency
is showing
what you know about art.
You can earn a degree in art.
Take the CSET in art.
Complete an approved subject
matter program in art,
or do a combination of the exam and coursework.
Early field experiences
include observations
in K-12 schools
or other settings
where you've observed
or worked with kids.
Once you're in,
there's usually a few different program pathways
that you can choose from.
For example, at CSUN,
we have an accelerated
one-year program as well as the traditional program,
which is about 3 to 4 semesters with student teaching.
We also have an internship
program for people
who can find employment
in a public school setting
while working towards
their credential.
Read through the list
of programs available.
There’s sure to be one out
there that's perfect for you.